<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Linux Gamer</title>
	<subtitle>(Eh near enough) Daily Linux, Art, Gaming and Programming Content on YouTube</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://linuxgamer.github.io/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://linuxgamer.github.io/"/>
	<updated>2022-08-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://linuxgamer.github.io/</id>
	<author>
		<name>CJ (Linux Gamer)</name>
		<email>charl.cj.monke@gmail.com</email>
	</author>
<entry>
		<title>Is Fedora Breaking TOO Much?</title>
		<link href="https://linuxgamer.github.io/content/posts/fedora-broken"/>
		<updated>2022-08-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://linuxgamer.github.io/content/posts/fedora-broken</id>
		<content type="html">
		<h1 id="is-fedora-breaking-too-much"><strong>Is Fedora Breaking TOO Much?</strong></h1>
		<br />
		<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
		<br />
		<p>Hi all, welcome back to another post. In today’s post I’m going to be discussing the different issues I’ve had whilst on Fedora, how I fixed or avoided them happening again. Sit tight, this is going to be a long one.</p>
		<br />
		<h2 id="issues-cropping-up">Issues cropping up</h2>
		<br />
		<p>Most of my issues and problems were caused by myself f*cking with my system, but others were caused by apps.
		The first issue I’m going to talk about today is system freezing and not doing anything, resulting in having to be forced off and turned back on again. This was caused by the package <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">brave-browser-nightly</code> which after uninstalling, the system didn’t crash anymore.</p>
		<br />
		<p>Next issue is Flatpak, Flatpaks are cool and good (when they work), I was trying to get them to show up in my app launcher (Rofi), but they wouldn’t I added the paths it said to $XDG_DATA_DIRS like the flatpak.run cli told me to do everytime I manually ran the apps. This then f*cked my whole system, Rofi only looked in that path, and so ONLY Flatpak apps were shown, no normal dnf installed ones.</p>
		<br />
		<p>Next was KDE Plasma not loading, cause by a segmentation fault for KSplashQML - which I believe was caused by the previous issue (Flatpak one ^). To fix this and the Flatpak issue, I reinstalled Fedora 36 KDE Spin onto my PC and it has worked like a charm since.</p>
		<br />
		<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
		<br />
		Although most of these issues were caused by me, but the issue caused by Brave was not. Why am I still using Fedora, well, I love it, Fedora fits my workflow perfectly, and that’s it. Arch could fit me better but I can’t be asked to go through that install at the moment. So Fedora (in my opinion) is still THE BEST Linux distro out there and is well suited for beginners.
		<br />
		</content>
</entry>

<entry>
		<title>Have I Found THE Best Flight Simulator Out There?</title>
		<link href="https://linuxgamer.github.io/content/posts/best-flightsim"/>
		<updated>2022-09-05T19:25:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://linuxgamer.github.io/content/posts/best-flightsim</id>
		<content type="html">
<h1 id="have-i-found-the-best-flight-simulator-out-there"><strong>Have I Found THE Best Flight Simulator Out There</strong></h1>

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>Hi all and welcome back to another blog post, today I’m going to be talking about flight simulators, and whether I have found the best one available. This is, of course, my personal opinions and nothing here should be taken as fact.</p>

<h2 id="flightgear-the-free-and-open-source-flight-simulator">Flightgear: The Free and Open Source Flight Simulator</h2>
<p>Flightgear was first released in 1997 (although development began in 1996). It is available on most operating systems including, Windows, macOS, Linux, IRIX and Solaris. Flightgear is ofter used in aerospace research and industry.</p>

<h2 id="comparison">Comparison</h2>
<p>Compared to many other flight simulators, such as Microsoft Flight Simulator 2020 and X-Plane, this one is not the best in all fields.
I am going to be reviewing FGFS against MSFS and X-Plane in multiple catagories.</p>

<h3 id="graphics-quality">Graphics Quality</h3>
<p>The default graphics settings leave something to be desired, but with newer updates adding photoscenery support, this could change (with a few little changes to some settings). But in this catagory, FGFS does not score very well, meaning that in this section the winner is MSFS and X-Plane (both with excellent graphics).</p>

<h3 id="price">Price</h3>
<p>FG is free (also open source), which makes it the winner compared to MSFS and X-Planes extortionate pricing.</p>

<h3 id="flying">Flying</h3>
<p>I have only ever tried FG (except from a couple of FSX sims in museums) and to be brutally honest, Flightgear has run better than anything else could ever run on the hardware that I have and use.</p>

<h4 id="aircraft">Aircraft</h4>
<p>Aircraft are community made in FG, which means if someone wants a plane (and it’s not already been made) they’ll make it themselves. This means that there is a few weird ones, but most of the ones that people want are in the game by default or easily downloadable.</p>

<h3 id="overall">Overall</h3>
<p>So overall, Flightgear wins because it’s free, has lots of aircraft and the best flying experience, and it has promising graphics coming in the future (in future updates).</p>

<p>So back to the original question, Is It THE Best Flight Sim available?, no, but it sure gives a good go at it.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading, have a wonderful morning, afternoon, evening, night, or day wherever you are! Bye for now!</p>
		</content>
</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Fedora Is The BEST Distro</title>
	<link href="https://linuxgamer.github.io/content/posts/fedora-the-best.md" />
	<updated>2022-10-06 T2:30:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://linuxgamer.github.io/content/posts/fedora-the-best.md</id>
	<content type="html">
<p><h1>Fedora Is The BEST Distro</h1></p>
<p><h2>Why Do I Keep Returning to Fedora</h2></p>
<p>Everytime I Distro hop, I find something wrong; with these issues, I decide to return to Fedora, is this because it is my favourite Distro and just works for me? Well, yes. All my issues are caused by something I've done wrong or by something that the Distro has done wrong.For example Arco Linux (my most recent hop), it wouldn't boot with "out of range pointer", tried troubleshooting and nothing, couldn't even boot to a tty. This incident reignited my trust in Fedora and to be completely honest, I don't know why I switched away.</p>
<p>There is quite a bit of hate on Fedora at the moment with the codec thing, but in my eyes, that is the right thing to do, to avoid legal action. Fedora is just for me, hence why I use it. I would use something else, but nothing else fits my workflow more than Fedora, and I can't wait to see what is to come what with the release of Fedora 37 soon, and other versions later on.</p>
<p><sub>! DISCLAIMER: I have in no way been influenced by Fedora, both monetary and emotionally for this article. !</sub></p>
<p>Links: <a href="https://linuxgamer.github.io">Website Home</a> | <a href="https://linuxgamer.github.io/posts">Other Posts</a></p>
	</content>
</entry>
<entry>
	<title>New Upload Schedule</title>
	<link href="https://linuxgamer.github.io/content/posts/new-upload-schedule.md" />
	<updated>2022-10-12 T10:00:00</updated>
	<id>https://linuxgamer.github.io/content/posts/new-upload-schedule.md</id>
	<content type="html">
<p><h1>New Upload Schedule</h1></p>
<p>I have recently been trying to improve my YouTube channel, including a new upload schedule.</p>
<p>The new posting schedule is as follows:</p>
<p>I will upload a new video once a week on either Monday or Friday</p>
<p>I will also try to get one longer video premiering once a month... but I cannot promise it.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Links: <a href="https://linuxgamer.github.io">Website Home</a> | <a href="https://linuxgamer.github.io/posts">Other Posts</a> | <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbBtLFxKBpcwt85EoP0kXRg">YouTube Link</a></p>
	</content>
</entry>

</feed>
